MAHESH KUMAR GUTAM

Software Developer

📞 9912299262 🏻 @ mahesh.gutam8686@gmail.com 🕜 linkedin.com/in/mahesh-kumar-gutam 💜 Hyderabad, India



SUMMARY

Software Developer with over 12 years of experience in backend development and cloud technologies. Led five implementations that boosted increased sales team engagement during high-volume campaigns. Enhanced testing protocols at JP Morgan, achieving a 40% reduction in deployment errors. Honored with the Iconic Team of the Year award at DBS Bank (2019-20). AWS Certified Developer - Associate (2024).

EXPERIENCE

Senior Member Technical Staff

Salesforce

前 01/2022

Software Engineer

JP Morgan & Chase

= 11/2020 - 01/2022

Senior Associate

DBS Bank Pvt Ltd

08/2018 - 11/2020

nisum

Software Engineer

Nisum Technologies Inc.

= 04/2017 - 08/2018

Software Developer

ADP India Pvt Ltd

= 11/2016 - 04/2017

NAPIER

Software Engineer

Napier Healthcare Solutions Inc.

= 09/2014 - 11/2016



Associate Software Developer

DEVAN Networks Pvt Ltd

= 07/2012 - 09/2014

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Technology

Institute of Aeronautical Engineering

AWARDS



Spot Bonus Award 03/2022 Received this award for resolving the critical issue faced by the most important customer(Stripe Inc.) -**Salesforce**



Way out of Your Way! (WOW) award for the first quarter of 02/2020 - DBS



Gladiator award for performance excellence for the second quarter of 05/2019 - DBS



Performance excellence award for the year of 06/2016 - Napier

PASSIONS



Build Scalable and Resilient Systems



Cloud Technologies and Digital Transformation



Solving Complex Technical Challenges

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS



Achievements

- · Led the development of a key Sales Cloud feature, earning high user satisfaction and top performer recognition from senior management - Salesforce
- · Recognized for enhancing JP Morgan's events orchestration service by introducing testing protocols that cut deployment errors by 40% -JP Morgan
- · Facilitated to winning the Iconic Team of the Year 2019-20 award by driving innovations that enhanced project delivery and client satisfaction
- · Led PAYLAH to become the first project to exit the KONY framework - DBS

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

SKILLS

REST API Github SQL Java/J2EE Microservices NoSql Redis **Spring Boot Spring Design Patterns Cloud Computing Distributed Systems** SDLC **Javascript**

PROJECTS

Salesforce Projects

Led five successful implementations to enhance data capture, doubling sales team adoption during high-volume campaigns

- Built automation tools that optimized IT processes, saving individual users 15 hours per month
- · Executed targeted outreach strategies that enhanced lead segmentation and drove over \$50k in new revenue within three months
- · Streamlined real-time insight generation from uploaded calls, slashing processing time by up to three hours per recording while maintaining top-tier accuracy
- Delivered 150+ actionable metrics by evaluating voice and video calls using the CRMA ECI dashboard, boosting lead management strategies
- · Architected robust backend systems for AFHT functionality in Salesforce, reducing latency by 40% for historical data access

JP Morgan & Chase Projects

Integration of Apache Kafka to process 100 million messages daily, ensuring high availability and reliable notification systems

Refined customer experience for 50k users by optimizing Kafka streaming for real-time notifications

DBS Projects

Migrated PAYLAH's backend from monolithic to microservices on PCF, reducing operational overheads and achieving 90% cloud deployment efficiency

- Played a pivotal role in migrating PAYLAH's backend from monolith to microservices, introducing bluegreen deployments for seamless releases there by reducing the deployment downtime by 99%
- Improved process compliance by 25% by mentoring team on the best practices